<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Black IO</title>
    <description>The ramblings of a developer/security enthusiast.  I made this site as a reference for multiple cyber security exams that I have taken.  Blogging about the material has helped quite a bit so maybe someone else will find it helpful too.</description>
    <link>http://projectblack.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://projectblack.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 18:47:54 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 18:47:54 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) is an open-source web application security project. The OWASP community includes corporations, educational organizations, and individuals from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This community works to create freely-available articles, methodologies, documentation, tools, and technologies. The OWASP Foundation is a 501(c)(3) charitable organization that supports and manages OWASP projects and infrastructure. It is also a registered non profit in Europe since June 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) is an open-source web application security project. The OWASP community includes corporations, educational organizations, and individuals from around the world. This community works to create freely-available articles, methodologies, documentation, tools, and technologies. The OWASP Foundation is a 501(c)(3) charitable organization that supports and manages OWASP projects and infrastructure. It is also a registered non profit in Europe since June 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 04:14:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://projectblack.io/web/2015/12/15/owasp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://projectblack.io/web/2015/12/15/owasp.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Future of Web Application Security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over a decade after their widespread adoption, web applications on the Internet today are still rife with vulnerabilities. Understanding of the security threats facing web applications, and effective ways of addressing these, are still underdeveloped within the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is currently little indication that the problem factors described in this chapter will disappear in the near future.  That said, the details of the web application security landscape are not static. Even though old and well-understood vulnerabilities such as SQL injection continue to appear, their prevalence is gradually diminishing. Furthermore, the instances that remain are becoming more difficult to find and exploit. New research in these areas is generally focused on developing advanced techniques for attacking more subtle manifestations of vulnerabilities that a few years ago could be easily detected and exploited using only a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second prominent trend has been a gradual shift in attention from attacks against the server side of the application to those that target application users. The latter kind of attack still leverages defects within the application itself, but it generally involves some kind of interaction with another user to compromise that user’s dealings with the vulnerable application. This is a trend that has been replicated in other areas of software security. As awareness of security threats matures, flaws in the server side are the first to be well understood and addressed, leaving the client side as a key battleground as the learning process continues. Of all the attacks described in this book, those against other users are evolving the most quickly, and they have been the focus of most research in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various recent trends in technology have somewhat altered the landscape of web applications. Popular consciousness about these trends exists by means of various rather misleading buzzwords, the most prominent of which are these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web 2.0 — This term refers to the greater use of functionality that enables user-generated content and information sharing, and also the adoption of various technologies that broadly support this functionality, including asynchronous HTTP requests and cross-domain integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud computing — This term refers to greater use of external service providers for various parts of the technology stack, including application software, application platforms, web server software, databases, and hardware. It also refers to increased usage of virtualization technologies within hosting environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most changes in technology, these trends have brought with them some new attacks and variations on existing attacks. Notwithstanding the hype, the issues raised are not quite as revolutionary as they may initially appear. We will examine the security implications of these and other recent trends in the appropriate locations throughout this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all the changes that have occurred within web applications, some categories of “classic” vulnerabilities show no sign of diminishing. They continue to arise in pretty much the same form as they did in the earliest days of the web. These include defects in business logic, failures to properly apply access controls, and other design issues. Even in a world of bolted-together applica- tion components and everything-as-a-service, these timeless issues are likely to remain widespread.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 05:34:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://projectblack.io/web/2015/11/12/future-of-web-security.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://projectblack.io/web/2015/11/12/future-of-web-security.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DEFCON: You Spent All That Money And You Still Got Owned</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This video is about one of our favorite lecturers from DEFCON, Joseph McCray.  McCray is very experienced in the CompSec world and does a very good job of explaining very difficult concepts in an easy to understand way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He swears quite often, so if you are offended by that then this video is not for you.  For everyone else, this guys is awesome and he doesn’t sound like the typical computer nerd that is trying to confuse you with his intelligence.  Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tJsNu0VRKYY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 04:14:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://projectblack.io/defcon/2015/11/12/you-spent-all-that-money-and-got-owned.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://projectblack.io/defcon/2015/11/12/you-spent-all-that-money-and-got-owned.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>DefCon</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
